coding  for wsd
Train on Word embeddings and predict the center word
Wordnet 3.0
Current Resource:
Given a word it's senses in order.
Each sense has lemmas, And it's lemma ranking AND part of speech
Possible candidates are all the senses of the centre word

To find:
How close is the predicted center word from the words in each sense?

Process:
Bi LSTM predicts the missing word.
Most likely if it is accurate, it would predict the popular sense associated with the context.
It is predicted because it occurs most times in tandem with the other. 
 

Assumption:
Most likely would be predicted word's first sense. The model must have seen the word in
tandem with the context the most number of times, so it equates context to the word.
It could equate it with something else.

If the word is the first sense, if it's closer 

Implement GVSM comparsion of a pair of documents.
VSM, scaled or not. Are frequencies augmented to not include bias?
Logarithmic scaling of IDF,TF
Outputting TF IDF scores for document and query.
pos tagging improves lemmatizer so..
pos tag,Lemmatize,remove stop words, feed it to the vectorizer
tokens are given to the pos_tag,to get postokens from which wordnet pos is obtained 
If the starting character is neither character nor number delete. 
Data preprocessing has one more step i.e tag the senses. There doesn't seem to be Multi sensed
words. Let's check the vocabulary. 
Pickle the tagged synsets to strings and using those strings one can get back Synset object using wn.synset(string)
method.
Tagged the words for which synsets are available with some errors especially in pos.
Check the reason for words that don't have synset. If they are single nouns add some mapping.
If they are words for which there is no mapping change remove them.
Then feed these features to getTfIdf.
Too many options for some of the words, and the meanings are hardly discernible.
change pos try, change spelling try, if there are any synsets to choose from.
Compute pairs of synsets sr. Find the dot product.
Tagging could be corrected later.
Still not clear on the logic behind finding pairwise dimensions.
Once that is clear I should obtain the maximal path between two senses.A function which takes two senses and
returns the SR.
One path or multiple pathhs between a pair of senses.
Is entire wordnet graph required or is it sufficient to build a graph,such that it contains the
Our vocab and thier neighbors, terms in the vocab could be related or connected by terms not in the vocab,
the path could contain them so best idea would be create a word net graph, where edges represent the relation type. 
Later weights need to be assigned to the graph based on the frequency of each edge type.
Should morpho-semantic links be included?Do they add to the similarity?
When adding synsets BFS is used with a closed set to avoid getting trapped in circles
Compute the log(number of nodes/number of nodes that have outgoing edge of type of 
a relation). Hypernym and hyponym are considered same.
Edge weight = (outgoing edges of the given type/edges of all types
outbound from a node) * Above factor
First the semantic network needs to be built.
Each edge is bi directional. s1 - s2 if one is a hypernym,other is a hyponym.
If one is a meronym the other is a holonym
How to link the antonyms.
antonyms, derivationally related forms, Pertainyms
For derivationally related forms, only consider the lemma with the 
same word as the synset. 
For antonyms get all the lemmas, choose the first lemma's antonym, then get
the antonym lemma's synset.
What are Pertainyms?
An adjective that classifies it's noun, example "a nervous disease"
the adjective nervous classifies the disease. 
Get the lemmas for the noun, take one lemma, get the pertainyms, 
map the pertainyms to synsets.Connect them using pertainym links.
Only possible issue could be edge weights going above one. Scale them to one.
Need to look at the domains relation.
Edge weight can only be 0 to 1.
12 relations. 
Adverbs 'r'

Frequently occuring type of edges have less weighting, rarer edge types have
more weighting. 
The idea is to build a graph such that all synsets of a pos are added and 
all their relations are found and edges are assigned a label based on the 
relation. 
Multi-edges are possible. So need to include that. 
Would it be possible to pickle the Graph? To consider later
Now given two synsets find the subgraph. 
Expand the network using BFS and obtain the subgraph.
Better of writing a function which expands the graph.
Add the nodes not in addedNodes.
Must recheck cause it is returning same number of nodes for
every pair that way there would be no need to compute a subgraph
for every pair. Somewhere nodes emmanating from the either ends,
become same. Find where, does it happen for every node.
Need to find the connecting condition.
If it returns the same thing for every pair what's the point
in computing it seperately for each pair.
Check the connecting condition.
Maintain the nodes emanating from either ends in seperate sets.
When either emantes a synset in the other set the synsets are 
considered connected and the network growth stops.
expander returning left,right seperately in a list?
Now that we have a network built,get the edge weights 
according to the formula above and calculate the relatedness
between two synsets.
Find the edge weights and then compute the path that maximises 
the relatedness.
Need to check when there is no connection between two synsets.
Would it be feasible to calculate SR within the function. 
Get the edge attributes.
Calculated inverse relation frequencies,Now should weight each edge
based on the above formula.Edge weight needs to be scaled from 0-1
Testing how to update the edges weights and also scale.
Need to fix this division by zero error, and scaling issue.
edges are weighted using the formula ((2d1*d2)/((d1+d2)*dmax))*w12
Find dmax
Could be found by going brutely going through all the nodes and 
finding the max depth.
Compute network uses wnGraph to build the subgraph.
WNGraph is symmetrified before it's used. Actually must consider making
it a static method.
Once subgraph is obtained, the edges are weighted and scaled.
wnGraph should be made instance Variable.
max depth =20
Iterate over the nodes beginning at the s1.
Find s1's successors, compute sr to those nodes.
Mark them as found

Visit the maximum sr node, expand it,. Visit the next max in the visited. 

Then I can use the path that maximises the S.R. using Djikstra's formula.

Should make the entire wordnet graph to compute once similar to
static methods in Java.

Once the edges are weighted, they are scaled according to 
(x-min)/(max-min)
Scaling has become a little tricky. 
If maximum is minumum or if the starting,
edge has  minimum node, then it is scaled to
zero. The ultimate edge weight needs to be between
zero to one, not the weighting?
In this scaling if there are two values,
the maximum will be 1, the minimum will be zero.
This is not ideal if only two edges are between the
senses, and the first edge is zero then the sr will 
be zero despite being closely related. 
Why am I getting values > 0 in the initial weighting
scheme. Because of the log(node+1/number of nds of given type edge)
factor I'm getting values greater than zero. Give up to a value
of 5 which is log(100000). But if the number of nodes is less it
gives a lesser value. The inverse scheme tends to give greater values for when
more nodes are present in the total graph. It should be checked.
The weighing scheme especially the log factoring seems a little flawed in terms
of going over 1 as well as tending to favor greater number 
Need to analyze the weighing scheme.
Either make it spit values between 0 - 1 right away, without needing to 
use the min, max scaling. Actually If the values are to be scaled it is
better to divide all the values by rms of all values. 
Any way need to take pen and paper and analyze. This entire scheme.
Can I use the Djikstra's algorithm now?
Yes I think I can.
Are there any edges with out weights.
Borders aren't expanded.But the few edges they do have are
weighted. 
Should  commutative property hold?
Why isn't the commutative propertry not holding?
Begin with all the synsets of given word.
Expand all the synsets,left and right

*** Take care of these logistics ***
Ingenuity should be used to include the ti
component. There are two ways of computing cosine
product one is to compute the dot product of n(n-1)/2
dimensions,other is to represent the items as n dimensional
non orthogonal synsets. Option 2 seems like a better option.
And term to term dot product is 1 if the term doesn't
one occurs in wordnet and the other doesn't, the similarity is zero.
If both occur and both are similar, then similarity depends on the
depth of the synsets.
Since we're tagging the synsets, the conditions 
The words not in wordnet can only have the possibility of matching
themselves, but since we're finding the relations between each unique 
pair without repetetion,such words will only show 0 sr's in all cases.
Since each unique tag is treated as vocab item, there is no chance that
the unique pairs contain the same synset. If we consider each unique pair
of words it could be possible that the words map to the same synset but that's
not the case. In case I'm planning to roll back to untagged datasets then 
maybe the synsets can be equal. But if the term is not in wn then it can't
match with anything except itself and it's matches contain anything but itself,
still such terms would amount to zero SR. So for Cosine similarity the untagged
data items aren't useful if each unique pair is considered a dimension.
*** n dimensional space requires the above logistics
and probably the other similarity measure
also the similar synset case must be considered if tagging is noy considered***
If each unique term is considered a dimension, then we can get n1.n1 and the
untagged terms might amount to some cosine similarity. Even there is a need
to calculate the sr for same synset in that case.
The question is do I define the above behavior while computing the SR.
****  for n-d   *********************************************
How the exclusion of the untagged terms affects the algorithm?	
It doesn't simply use a function to calculate tfidfs by using only
tagged features if the algorithm is n(n-1)/2 d.
Either implement cosine similarity or choose the other text-text similarity
computing method used in the research paper.
*** Take care of these logistics ***

Then I can use the option of either merging edge types,
make it flexible to do so.
Store code in cloud. Maybe store in Github using Git or something
to track the changes.
Need to cleanup as well.
Make wordnet utils a class or something?
wn 3.0 edge weight
0.5868585346734231
0.05649983613927667
0.08097848731026328
0.05992526633543196
0.005250130512184157
0.01249623285020495
0.026425217753609464
0.0013438226154147653
0.0021046633609069485
0.0007246102338020792
0.004765959128689131
3.623051169010397e-05
4.9405243213778136e-05
0.0013471162982956837
0.0028786788379228058
0.12309645715000914
0.03521935104566197


wordnet2.0 edge type and probability of occurence
hypernym/hyponym 0.61,nominalization 0.147,category domain 0.094,
part meronym/holonym 0.0367,region domain 0.0238,
similar 0.02,usage domain 0.016 ,member meronym/holonym 0.014 ,
antonym 0.0105 ,verb group 0.01 ,also see 0.0091 ,
attribute 0.00414 ,entailment 0.00195,
cause 0.00158,substance meronym/holonym 0.00089,
 derived 0.0003,participle of 3.4E − 06

Added edges
inst_hyponym
mem_meronym
part_meronym
sub_meronym
top_domain
reg_domain
use_domain

Classified.
Statified.
Let's check the speed now. Can leave it on overnight and check it's speed in
this system. Time taken = 5 Mins at 11 
We have GPU in the other device which might improve the performance. 
For which GIT logistics must be taken care of. 
Upload,download later. 
5766  iterations completed 11 hours taken
7140
How to compute n1 and n2.
119+118+117+.... = 5766
(120-1)+(120-2)+(120-3)+..
120*n1 - (n1(n1-1)/2) = n2+
7088 diff 52 
Might have missed an iteration.
If it's 119 it is overshot 67
len(features) -1 = 119 
n1 can be 118
at n1 = 0, n2 can be 1-119
Need to look more closely.

7088 iterations only obtained why?
Git logistics:
Removed the files from git but it also seemed to remove from disk
See if there is a way to restore those files and then remove those
files only in Git.
One way is to try restoring it to previous commit to my knowledge.











Have words in lemmatized format
Have different synsets
Need synsets associated with each WORD
Generate list of (candidates,occurences,pos) for each word
dict of list of list of tuples(candidate word,occurences,pos)
Wordnet data seems prepared
Feature set selection.

dog's last sense


got synsets
synsets lemmas 
from lemmas and synsets, lemma numbers 

word:
senses

// if synset is named after the lemma it is the first sense


Could include POS tagging to differentiate Nouns from verbs
Problem not all wordnet words will be available could be.
Get all the wordnet words.
Lemma and vocab. We also need lemma to word mapping or vice versa.

how to Process wiki corpus?
Check 2 //
To process wiki test the time.

If trained on Wiki corpus it will take long before any results.
Center word and the possible candidates include the senses of the center word.
synsets the center word is part of, check for the sense that is number one in occurence.
For less occuring synsets try to adjust the weight.

Maybe use Google colab
It will take how long I don't know.

Analyze: 
Compare my method to these two methods.
Also look at semi-supervised methods.
Context clustering ie word sense induction
Word clustering check wiki for methods.
After Lunch.


Check the accuracy Sense Eval
Then apply it to tracing
